字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
间谍同盟
[法属摩洛哥 1942年]
你妻子会穿着一件紫色的裙子
Your wife will be wearing a purple dress.
注意找蜂鸟
Look for the hummingbird.
[吉简思饭店]
朋友们 同事们
Friends, colleagues...
还有觉得他是我想象出来的的那几位
...and those who thought he was a figment of my imagination...
这位就是从巴黎远道而来
...may I introduce, all the way from Paris...
给了我一个大惊喜的
and completely out of the blue...
我最棒 最棒的丈夫！
my wonderful, wonderful husband!
晚上好
Bonsoir.
我以为你要永远困在法国回不来了呢
I thought he was stuck in France forever!
这是真的了 真有你这个人！
So it is true. You do exist!
没错
Oui.
莫里斯 你能待多久？
Oh Maurice, how long do we have?
公司给了我六个星期的假期
The company gave me six weeks leave.
六个星期？已经够长了
Six weeks? That is a lifetime!
你知道吗 克里斯汀经常说起你
You know, Christine never stops talking about you.
没说我坏话吧
All good things I hope.
全都是好话
All amazing.
那我可得表现得好点了
Oh hell, now I have to be amazing.
女士们 先生们 我们夫妻俩几个月没见了
Ladies and gentlemen...I haven't seen my wife in many months.
所以请大家见谅 我就先带她回去了…
I know you will forgive me if I take her home...
…我们得重新熟悉一下对方
...we must renew our acquaintance.
我把钱给你们
I must give you some money.
别别别 快走吧 我们来结账
No. Go, go. We will settle the bill.
你还是去把欠你丈夫的帐给清了吧
You go settle your overdue account with your husband.
莫里斯 你有一个好妻子
Maurice. You have a wonderful wife.
等你们搞完了 一定得跟我们聚聚
When you're settled, we must all meet.
说说开采磷矿的事儿
You can tell us all about phosphate mining.
我很期待
I look forward to it.
- 那再见了  - 再见啦
- à bient?t.  - Bonsoir.
- 再见  - 再见
- Bonsoir.  - Bonsoir.
谢谢
Merci.
表演得不错
Not bad.
你也表现得不差
You weren't so bad yourself.
马克斯·瓦坦
Max Vatan.
玛丽安·博塞茹尔
Marian ne Beauséjour.
我听说过很多你在情报组的事
I've heard a lot about you around the circuit.
你的事我也听说了不少
I've heard a lot about you.
往前直走 转弯时我告诉你
Keep going straight. I'll tell you when to turn.
你在迪耶普待过
You were in Dieppe for a while?
丈夫会在自己抽烟前
A husband would offer his wife a cigarette
先给妻子一根烟
before lighting his own.
往这里右转
Turn right here.
谢谢
Thank you.
巴黎出什么事了 你的整个情报组都被清除了
What went wrong in Paris? Your entire circuit was taken out.
我从来不跟任何人讨论跟作战不相关的情报
I never discuss non-relevant operational information with anyone.
那我说点相关的
I'll try to stay relevant then.
那就非常感谢了
That would be appreciated.
他们信任你吗
Do they trust you?
两个月前 我被提拔进了大使馆联络处
Two months ago, I got promoted to the Embassy Liaison Department.
每天跟德国使团打交道
I deal with the German legation every day.
但他们信任你吗
But do they trust you?
你觉得呢
How did it look?
他们好像挺喜欢你
They seemed to like you.
我也喜欢他们
And I like them.
我投入了真感情
I keep the emotions real.
所以才能骗得过
That's why it works.
不要减速
Don't slow down.
在卡萨布兰卡就这么开车
This is how you drive in Casablanca.
既然你来了 我就炫耀一下
Now that you're here I can show you off.
我们在这个公寓待不了多久
We won't be in the apartment much.
我得让别人相信你是我丈夫
I have to go out there and sell you.
我们一定得小心
We'll have to be careful.
我跟大家说我丈夫是巴黎来的
I've told everyone my husband is from Paris.
还有呢
And?
还有
And...
你的法语很好
Your French is good,
但是巴黎口音差劲透了
but your Parisian accent is terrible.
我已经练了好几个月了
I've been working on it for months.
说说看
Let's hear it.
我说过了
That was it.
那麻烦就大了
Oh. So then we're in trouble.
你说的是魁北克法语
That was pure Quebec.
要说你是法属摩洛哥人 也许还能说得过去
With French Moroccans you might be okay,
不过在宴会前 要是碰到真正的巴黎人就要小心了
but we'll have to be careful in front of real Parisians until the party.
宴会在十天后 我的邀请函没问题吧
The party's in 10 days. Is my invitation gonna be a problem?
既然你来了
Now that you're here,
我会安排你跟霍巴先生见面
I'm going to set up a meeting with Herr Hobar.
之后就看你的了
And then it's up to you.
你能在这个小公寓待上十天吗
Can you stand 10 days in this tiny little place,
魁北瓜
Le Québécois?
其实这里也不差
It's not so bad.
有热水 有时候
Water's hot, sometimes.
我睡沙发
I'll take the couch.
其实你要睡屋顶上
Actually, you'll sleep on the roof.
那儿更凉快
It's cooler.
而且卡萨布兰卡的男人跟老婆上完床后
And in Casablanca, the roof is where husbands go
就会去屋顶睡觉
after they've made love to their wives.
你来的第一晚
The neighbors will find it curious
要是我不上来看你 邻居们会好奇的
if I don't come to visit you on your first night.
我经常跟帕杰诺特夫人和珀蒂夫人说起你
I've told Madame Torgenot and Madame Petit all about you.
她们俩这会儿该兴奋了
They'll be very excited.
肯定会猜测我们俩上完床了
They'll guess that the sex is already over.
刚刚感觉还不错
And it was great, by the way.
然后
Then,
你去屋顶上了
you went to the roof.
我很想你
I missed you
因为我已经孤枕难眠好几个月了
because I've been sleeping alone so many months.
所以我上来告诉你我爱你
So I came up to tell you I love you.
你想得很周到
You're very thorough.
所以我还活着
That's why I'm still alive.
我们现在应该聊天
Now we should talk.
说笑
And laugh.
都结婚了 有什么好笑的
Mmm. We're married. Why would we laugh?
吻我
Kiss me.
继续说
Now talk.
告诉我 战后你想做什么
Tell me what you'll do after the war.
我不知道战后要做什么
I don't know what I'll do after the war.
看
Look.
可爱的珀蒂夫人住在七号公寓
The lovely Madame Petit in apartment seven.
她嫁给了一个德国坦克上尉
She's married to a German tank captain.
她正在看着我们
And she's watching us.
所以我们应该有说有笑
So we should talk. And laugh.
好吧
Okay.
战后我要买个牧场
After the war, I'm buying a ranch.
还要有马
With horses.
买牧场
A ranch!
你是说电影里那种
You mean, like in the movies?
牛仔
Cowboys? Bang, bang?
对
Yeah.
你只是随便这么一说，还是真这么想的？
Are you just saying this to say something, or is it real?
是真的 那是
Mmm, it's real.
一个大草原上的牧场
It's a ranch on a prairie
在梅迪辛哈特市郊
outside a place called Medicine Hat.
我现在知道你是开玩笑了
Now I know you're joking.
你觉得自己真能去那里？
You think you'll ever get there?
不对
Well,
梅迪辛哈特不止是个地方吧
I guess that's not the point of Medicine Hat, huh?
是的
No.
好了 倾述一下并不难 是吧
Okay. That wasn't so hard, was it?
这时候呢 我会跟你说我爱你
Now this is the part where I tell you I love you
然后把你留在这里数星星
and leave you to count the stars,
做男人在屋顶会做的事
or whatever it is men do on their rooftops.
我爱你
Je t'aime.
我也爱你
Je t'aime aussi.
再亲我一下
Now kiss me again.
晚安
Bon nuit.
你婶婶在等你
Your aunt is waiting for you
我有好多婶婶
I have a lot of aunts
哪个婶婶在等我
Which aunt is waiting for me
你婶婶安托瓦内特在等你
Your aunt Antoinette is waiting for you
安托瓦内特
antoinette
安托瓦内特 安 安托瓦内特
antoinette, an...antoinette
你可以进来了
You can come in now.
听好了
Voilà.
你的角色老派内敛
You are somewhat formal and reserved.
不过很喜欢昂贵的衣服
But you like expensive clothes.
鞋子总是擦得锃亮
And your shoes are always polished.
我告诉大家你是个严肃的天主教徒
I told everyone you're quite a serious Catholic.
至少你可以闻起来像巴黎人
At least you can smell like a Parisian.
你自己选衣服吧
I'll leave you to choose.
我离开伦敦前 盖伊·桑斯特要我跟你说声谢谢
Before I left London, Guy Sangster asked me to say thank you.
我们一起开过莱桑德式联络机
We flew Lizzies together.
还记得盖伊吗 一九四一年你从迪耶普把他救了出来
You remember Guy? You got him out of Dieppe in '41.
好吧 他怎么说我的
Okay. What did he say about me?
他说你美丽动人
He said you were beautiful.
很出色
And good.
干这样的活出色可一点也不美
Being good at this kind of work is not very beautiful.
你看起来不错
You look okay.
走吧
Let's go.
你好
Bonjour.
麻烦来两杯咖啡
Two cups of coffee.
克里斯汀
Kristen
- 你好  - 你还好吗
- Hello.  - how are you?
你好
Hello.
你好吗 克劳德
How are you, Claude
- 弥撒很不错  - 对 非常棒
- It was a lovely mass...  - Yes, very good
- …布道也很好  - 哎
- ...good sermon as well.  - Hey
你给他弄到大使馆宴会的邀请函了吗？
Did you get him an invitation to the Ambassador's party yet?
还在想办法
We're working on it.
我们下周要跟政府的人一起吃饭
We're meeting some Government people for dinner next week.
你们也来吧
You should come.
你们看看他的样子
Look at his face.
笑得真够假的
That fake smile.
莫里斯不太擅长交际
Maurice isn't very sociable.
就算为了太太我们也得去 对吧？
We'll do it for the women, yes?
对
Oui.
好 那我们下周见 太好了
Good. Until next week.
- 再见  - 再见
- Au revoir.  - Au revoir.
谢谢
Merci.
早啊
Bonjour.
看起来维希政府的人都被你迷住了 夫人
You seem to have all Vichy under your spell, Madame Berne.
转过身笑一下 魁北瓜
Turn around and smile, Québécois.
早啊
Bonjour.
怎么了
?a va?
十点钟方向的德国军官 我认得他
The German officer at ten o'clock. I think I recognize him.
他是德国军情局马赛分局的人
He was attached to the Abwehr. In Marseille.
他审问过我
He interrogated me once.
他没看你 他在看报纸
He hasn't seen you. He's reading his paper.
谢谢
Merci.
你肯定是他
You're sure that it's him?
对
Oui.
确定吗？
Really sure?
六成确定
60% sure.
给我接维希政府警察局
Put me through to the Vichy Commissariat of Police.
快点
Quickly.
请你稍等
Please wait a moment
好 我等着
Yes... I'll hold.
那儿好像有人噎着了
Sounds like somebody's choking back there.
好了 亲爱的
Okay, chérie.
我们走吧
Mademoiselle.
冒着雨赶了三个小时的路
The rain drove three hours of the road
我们终于到地儿了
We finally reached our destination
可是眼前根本就不是
But it's not at all
他们跟我们描述过的漂亮的豪华建筑
The beautiful luxury buildings they described to us
而是一个小农场
It's a small farm
一片漆黑
Pitch black
我们已经准备回去了
We're ready to go back
这时一个穿着破旧的小个子男人出来了
Then a little man in shabby clothes came out
他对我们说
He said to us
伯尔尼先生和太太
Mr. and Mrs. Bern
见我不太高兴
See I'm not happy
莫里斯就对我说
And Maurice said to me
亲爱的 你要知道
Honey, you need to know
在人的回忆里
In the memory of man
什么东西都要比现实中大得多
Everything is much bigger than reality
莫里斯 我给你介绍个朋友 文森特
Maurice, meet my friend Vincent...
…他也是巴黎人
...he's also from Paris.
亲爱的
My love!
好无聊
I'm bored.
陪我跳舞
Dance with me.
你真够疯的 伯尔尼夫人
You're utterly crazy, Madame Berne.
对啊 稍微疯狂一下感觉很好的
Yes. You could do with being a little crazy yourself.
真机灵
Well played.
小心那个人
Watch out for him.
那些家伙嫉妒得想杀了我
A lot of jealous guys giving me the evil eye.
那是因为他们知道我爱你
It's because they know I'm in love with you.
显而易见
It's very obvious.
嗯
Mmm.
巴黎出什么事了
What went wrong in Paris?
V部门撇下我们不管了
V Section left us hanging out to dry.
你怎么逃掉的
How'd you get away?
我跑
I ran.
我跑 不停地跑
And ran, and kept on running.
珀蒂夫人正在窗户后面看着我们
Madam Petit. Lurking in the window.
晚安
Bonsoir.
跟我说说明天要见的
This Herr Hobar we're meeting tomorrow,
这位霍巴先生
what can you tell me about him?
他是大使的联络人
He's the Ambassador's liaison.
来自科隆的纳粹高管
A high-ranking Party member from Cologne.
喜欢高尔夫和赌博
He likes golf and gambling.
他是我们最后的障碍
He's our final hurdle.
你有两秒钟
You have two seconds.
开始
Go.
枪会贴在摆香槟的桌子下面
The guns will be taped under the champagne table.
大使本人会在八点半准时到达
The Ambassador arrives at precisely 8:30.
他要是迟到呢
If he's late?
他是德国人 不会迟到的
He's German. He'll be on time.
你怎么不会用斯特恩式轻机枪
How come you don't know Stens?
我会用轻机枪
I do know Stens.
只是没看到你上了保险栓
I didn't see you set the travel safety.
那你晚上用的机枪没问题吧
You'll be okay to use a Sten on the night, though?
需要的话我用餐具都没问题
I would be okay if I had to use cutlery.
大使到达五分钟后 八点三十五分开始佯攻
The diversion attack will happen five minutes later at 8:35.
剩下的就都交给上帝了
And then everything will be in God's hands.
很好
Good.
希望他会用保险栓
Hopefully, he'll know how to work the safety.
好热
It's hot.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
考验你
Testing you
就像你考验我一样
the way you tested me.
我知道你拿着武器 瓦坦先生
I know you are armed with a weapon, Mr. Vatan.
我只想看看你的保险栓上了没有
I'm just checking your safety catch is engaged.
看
There.
我们第一次吵架
We had our first fight.
现在又和好了 对吧
Now we're okay again, yes?
玛丽安
Marianne,
你知道有人跟搭档上了床
we both know people who've fucked each other.
然后搞砸了任务死掉了
Then they fucked up, and now they're fucking dead.
你真够直接的
Wow, that's a lot of fucks.
把你的扣子都扣好
Fasten your goddamn buttons.
其实 马克斯
Actually, Max,
他们的错并不是在这种情况下上床
the mistake people make in these situations isn't fucking.
而是相爱
It's feeling.
等很久了吗
Have you been waiting long?
没
Non.
霍巴先生可以见你们了
Herr Hobarwill see you now.
谢谢
Oh, merci.
不了
Non.
我丈夫正在戒烟
My husband's trying to cut down.
说是打起仗来大家都抽得太凶了
He says the war makes everyone smoke too much.
我只知道镇子上的人都在说他的好
I've only heard good things about him around town.
他的好
Good things.
请坐 二位
Sit down, please.
你丈夫不会说英语吗
Your husband doesn't speak English?
就会一点儿
Only a little.
你妻子问我可不可以带你去参加大使馆的舞会
Your wife has asked if she could bring you to the Ambassador's Ball tomorrow.
是这样…但是
Yes, but...
…不行的话我也能理解
...if it's a problem, I understand.
他好像不太想去
He doesn't seem to want to come.
哦 瓦朗斯街那儿有场牌局
Oh.There is a stupid poker game in the Rue Valence.
明白了
I see.
你说了我什么？
What are you saying about me?
别让我丢人 你一定要去 就这么定了
Don't embarrass me. You're coming and that's that.
你丈夫玩扑克吗
So, your husband plays poker?
他特别着迷
Oh, he's obsessed.
我也是 我也是
As am I. As am I.
现在切牌 大牌赢
And now we cut. High card wins.
赢什么
Wins what?
要是他的牌大
If his card is higher than mine,
他就可以去打牌了
he can go to his poker game.
不然的话 就必须参加宴会
If it's lower, he must come to the party.
这也太荒唐了
This is too absurd.
洗牌吧 先生
Shuffle, Mr. Berne.
谁牌大谁赢
High card wins.
他是采矿的
Mining?
对
Yes.
是开采磷矿的 对吧
He works with phosphate, right?
没错
That's right.
切牌吧 伯尔尼先生 为了你的自由
Now cut, Mr. Berne. For your freedom.
真遗憾
Too bad.
这下你玩不了牌了
No pokerforyou.
谢谢
Merci.
- 谢谢  - 告辞
- Merci.  - Au revoir.
呃
Ah. Uh...
还有一件事 新发的邀请函
One more thing. Boring. Procedure.
要走个无聊的小程序
For new names on the list.
伯尔尼先生
Mr. Berne...
请在这里写下磷酸盐的化学式
...write down the chemical formula for phosphate, please.
我们明天见
See you both tomorrow.
快要开始了
So, it's in the cards.
我们有机会名留青史了
We get our chance to make history.
我睡不着
I couldn't sleep.
嗯
Mmm.
我不会让你失望的 魁北瓜
I won't let you down, Le Québécois.
我知道
I know.
我们出去吧 去看日出
Let's get out of here. Let's go watch the sunrise.
有多大几率
What are our odds?
活下来吗
Of surviving?
六四开
60-40.
六成死
Against.
两个人都活下来的几率更小
Both of us, I don't know.
跟我说说梅迪辛哈特吧
So, tell me about Medicine Hat.
遍地绿色 山丘起伏 水流清澈
Pretty green. Rolling hills. Clear water.
事情变得糟糕时 我就会想起那里
Just a place I go when things get dark.
你呢
You?
你想去哪儿
You have a place?
等仗打完了
When the war is over,
我在哪儿都无所谓
it won't matter where I am.
我们该走了
We should be going.
要是我们明天死了
If we're dead tomorrow,
没人会知道
no one would know.
你看起来真美
You look beautiful.
枪呢
The guns?
处理了
Gone.
很好
Bien.
谢谢 魁北瓜
Merci, Le Québécois.
我是安大略人
I'm from Ontario.
谢谢
Merci.
八点三十二了
It's 8:32.
离佯攻还有三分钟
Three minutes until the diversion.
我发现这种时候想点搞笑的事能放松神经
In this kind of situation, I find it useful to think about something funny.
笑一下或者说句话
Smile or something.
你看起来很美
You look beautiful.
这句说过了
You already told me that.
是吗
Quoi?
能正眼看我吗
Can you even see me?
不能
Not really.
- 啊 你们俩  - 晚上好
- Ah. You two.  - Good evening.
晚上好 你好吗
Good evening. How are you?
很好 谢谢 你呢？
Very well, thank you. And you?
还行
Not bad.
那么…
So...?
宴会…很有意思
So... It's lovely.
嗯
Mmm.
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler.
他迟到了
He's late.
他在干什么？
What's he doing?
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen
党员同志们
Party comrades
德国和法国
Germany and France
这两个伟大的国家之间的联盟提醒着我们
The alliance between the two great nations reminds us
我们正处在一场非常艰巨的战争之中
We are in a very difficult war
仅仅在过去这短短的一年
Only in the past year
走
Move!
没有人追我们
No one's following us.
我们活下来了 马克斯 我们俩都活下来了
We're alive, Max. We're both alive.
跟我去伦敦
Come with me to London.
跟我去伦敦 然后嫁给我
Come with me to London and be my wife.
[三个星期后]
[今晚灯火管制开始时间]
[19:15]
乔治
George?
向我敬礼 法国人
Salute me, Frenchman.
- 去死吧  - 在办公室跟死了差不多
- Go to hell.  - This is hell, it's an office.
噢！
Oh.
我得走了 乔治 晚点请我喝酒
Gotta go, George. Buy me a drink later.
马克斯 你好像得意洋洋的 这样子真恶心
Max, you appear to be walking on air. It's revolting!
- 早上好 长官  - 你好
- Good morning, sir.  - Morning.
你说弗兰克想见我
They said Frank wanted to see me?
对 现在
Yes, straight away.
马克斯 请记住 你只要回答“是 长官”“不是 长官”就行了
Max, please remember you're in the land of "Yes, sir, no, sir."
不要乱扔东西或打人
Don't throw anything or hit anyone.
好的
Got it.
他可以见你了
He's ready to see you.
弗兰克
Frank.
都说你有消息了
They said you had news.
对 对 我是有消息了 中校
Yes, yes, I have news, Wing Commander,
关于玛丽安·博塞茹尔的消息
regarding Marianne Beauséjour.
已经三个星期了
It's been three fucking weeks.
长官
"Sir."
已经三个星期了 长官
"It's been three fucking weeks, sir."
It's been three fucking weeks, sir.
经过直布罗陀海峡地区
After a thorough vetting procedure carried out by
V部门的彻底审查后
V Section in Gibraltar,
玛丽安·博塞茹尔
Marianne Beauséjour
已经批准登陆英格兰了
has been approved for passage to England.
没事了 中校
That'll be all, Wing Commander.
马克斯
Max.
你是个傻瓜
You're a bloody fool.
是 长官 谢谢长官
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
战地婚姻从来都长久不了
Marriages made in the field never work.
您说的对 长官
You're absolutely right, sir.
顺便说一下 欢迎参加我们的婚礼
You're invited to the wedding, by the way.
恭喜你们
Bravo!
小心点 马克斯 稳住
Careful, careful, Max! Hold on.
请过来 过来
Here we go. Come on.
好了
That's it.
进来吧 亲爱的
Come on in, darlings.
别问我为什么是真的
Don't ask me why that's true.
我们能有什么
What the hell have we here?
话说有趣的是 全伦敦就一样东西不限量
Here's a fun fact. Only thing in London not rationed,
香槟
champagne!
香槟和性爱
Champagne and sex.
天啊 马克斯 你姐姐执迷于此啊
Oh, my God, Max, your sister is obsessed!
这样不好吗
Yes. Isn't it wonderful?
敬我曾经冰山似的弟弟
To my formerly permafrosted brother,
他终于被爱情融化了
thawed at last by love.
还真有诗意
That's rather poetic.
看在上帝的份上
Oh, for goodness sake!
说实话 以后我会想念大轰炸的
Honestly, I'll miss the Blitz.
真的 这种时候没人在乎谁对谁做了什么
I will. No one cares who does what to who.
所以我们应该敬战争和自由
So we should be drinking to war. And freedom.
- 敬战争  - 敬自由
- To war!  - To freedom.
玛丽安 我很想恭喜你结婚
Marianne, I would offer you my congratulations,
但是我认识马克斯很久了
but I've known Max a long time.
所以我只能祝你好运了
I'll just wish you good luck.
不不不 我哥哥就是个坐在无聊的办公室里的
Mmm, no, no, no. Now my brother is just an ordinary man flying a desk
普通文员
in some boring office.
马克斯这种天才
Oh, oh, a talented boy like Max
弗兰克可留不了多久
won't be behind a desk with Frank for long.
V部门的那些幽灵
Our spooky friends from V Section,
肯定会来召唤的 就在你想不到的时候
they will come calling just when you least expect it.
你觉得怎么样 瓦坦夫人
You entirely okay, Madame Vatan?
好极了
Entirely.
呼吸 呼吸 呼吸
Breathe, breathe, breathe.
快到外面去
Get up! Get outside!
撑住 把她抬出去 快点
Hang on! Get her out. Quickly.
快点
Quickly.
我需要那个推车 帮我
I need that trolley. Help me.
把它扶起来 快点
Get this up now. Come on.
把她扶上去 离墙远点
Get her on it. Away from the wall.
快点 快点
Come on. Come on.
来个人帮忙 过来帮我
Help me, someone! Come and help me!
对 快来帮我
That's it. I need some help!
赶快给我找个灯过来
Get me some light over here now!
快出来了
Very close.
好姑娘
Good girl.
非常好 使劲儿
Pant for me. Good girl.
这就是我
C'est moi.
这就是真正的我 真实得如同站在上帝面前
This is really me, as I am before God.
是个女孩
It's a girl.
安娜
Anna...
你来了
Anna... it's you.
[一年后]
[安娜的安全地带]
嗯
Mmm.
给 庆祝一下
There. A celebration.
- 庆祝什么  - 庆祝你五十七天来休的第一个周末
- For what?   - Your first weekend off in 57 days.
我数着呢
I counted.
是母鸡下的蛋？
Are the eggs from the hens?
是我们母鸡下的蛋
From our hens.
所以养鸡是一笔好投资
Ah, so they were a good investment, hmm?
是不是啊
Weren't they?
马克斯
Max,
我们去荒野采蘑菇吧
let's go to the heath and pick mushrooms.
明天的宴会我要做俄式炖肉
Tomorrow I want to serve stroganoff at the party.
什么宴会
What party?
亲爱的 我交了很多新朋友 他们都想见你
Oh, darling, I've got lots of new friends who are dying to meet you.
你会喜欢他们的
You'll like them.
其中有难民 知识分子 波西米亚人
They're refugees. Intellectuals. Bohemians.
汉普斯特这儿有很多有趣的人
Hampstead is full of interesting people.
你好啊
Hello.
可怜的马克斯
Poor Max.
以前我们在卡萨布兰卡 假装过你不喜欢宴会
In Casablanca, we pretended you hated parties,
结果呢 竟然是真的
and voilà, it's true!
新保姆叫什么？
What's the new nanny's name again?
- 辛克莱尔小姐  - 辛克莱尔小姐
- Miss Sinclair.  - Miss Sinclair.
- 你好 辛克莱尔小姐  - 你好
- Hello, Miss Sinclair.  - Hello.
马克斯要休三天假 不错吧
Max has three days off. Isn't that great?
她刚睡醒
She just woke up.
我们很快回来
We won't be long.
就去采点蘑菇
We're just gonna pick some mushrooms.
不用着急
Oh, take your time.
我很乐意照顾她
It's always my pleasure.
- 好  - 再见
- Bye.  - Bye-bye.
我得去接安娜了
I have to go and get Anna.
就这一次 别接了 就这一次
Just once you can ignore it. Just once.
汉普斯特 二三五
Hampstead 235.
好 下午三点 我会到的
Sure. 1500. I'll be there.
你什么时候回来
When will you be back?
你知道的 我也不知道
You know I don't know.
到底什么事这么重要
What the hell is it that's so important?
解放你的祖国
Liberating your country.
那你一定得去
Then you must go.
早 玛格丽特
Good morning, Margaret.
- 下午好 长官  - 下午好
- Good afternoon, sir.  - Afternoon.
乔治在你办公室
George is in your office.
我记得你是说在你食堂见面
I thought you said to meet you in the mess.
我说谎了
Uh, I lied.
你要见的不是我
It isn't me you're here to see.
- 你…  - 不
- Oh, do you...  - No.
V部门想跟你谈谈
No, V Section want to speak to you.
那怎么不是他们打电话
Well, why didn't they call me?
因为他们有话
Because V Section, they never say
从不明说 说了也不是那意思
what they mean and they never mean what they say.
而且从不在电话里说
And they never say anything on the phone.
你看吧 我就说过他们会来找你的吧 马克斯
I told you they'd come for you eventually, didn't I, Max?
我真聪明
Such a clever boy.
我看我可以提前祝贺你升职了
Well, I suppose I ought to congratulate you on your promotion.
既然你好像很清楚的样子 是什么职位
Since you seem to know so much, what is the position?
老兄 这可就大大超出我的安全级别了
Oh, it goes way, way above my level of security, old man.
我就是个传话的
I'm just the messenger boy.
- 瓦坦中校  - 弗兰克
- Wing Commander.  - Frank.
坐下吧
Have a seat.
我们好像不认识
We haven't been introduced.
好了 弗兰克 不管是什么工作 我都不干
Okay, Frank, whatever the job is, I don't want it.
我很喜欢跟你共事
I'm perfectly happy to stay with you.
马克斯
Max,
我恐怕事情并不是你想的那样
I'm afraid this really isn't what you think it is.
只是 好吧…
And, well,
这件事有点不太容易说出口
there's no easy way to say what we're about to say.
我们认为你的妻子是德国间谍
We believe your wife is a German spy.
好吧 等等 等等
Okay, wait. Wait.
说真的 弗兰克 这位是谁
Seriously, Frank, who is this?
我是一个捕鼠人
I'm a rat catcher.
而且我的军衔比你高 所以你可以称呼我为长官
I also outrank you, so you can call me "sir."
你得听他的 马克斯
You have to listen to him, Max.
他的军衔比我们俩的都高
He outranks both of us.
过去七天里
Over the past seven days,
V部门监听到了用一台无线电发报机
V Section has intercepted coded messages
从伦敦发往柏林的加密信息
being sent from London to Berlin on a WT transceiver.
我们还没追查到具体的地址
We haven't traced the signal to an address yet,
但信号是从伦敦北部的海格特地区发出的
but it's coming from the Highgate region of North London,
而这些情报
and the information
跟特别行动处在法国的作战行动有关
concerns the activities of SOE circuits in France.
我们破译的一份信息显示 那个特务处发报人
In one transcript, the agent refers to his source as,
为“小姐” 所以发报人是个女的
"Fr?ulein." So it's a woman.
好吧 好吧 弗兰克 我们能单独谈谈吗
Okay, okay, Frank, can we speak alone for a moment?
瓦坦中校
Wing Commander Vatan,
你跟你妻子说过工作上的事吗
do you ever speak to your wife about your work?
好吧
Okay.
长官 趁我还没失控
Uh, sir, before this thing gets out of hand,
我能说句话吗
may I speak? Hmm?
May I speak?
- 可以  - 可以
- Yes.  - Yes?
我的妻子是玛丽安·博塞茹尔
My wife is Marianne Beauséjour.
玛丽安·博塞茹尔曾经负责
Marianne Beauséjour ran the most
巴黎最高效的反抗军情报小组
effective resistance circuit in Paris
直到V部门在一九四一年搞砸了一切
until V Section fucked it up for her in '41.
我们在卡萨布兰卡认识
We met in Casablanca,
并且在那里一起刺杀了德国大使
where together we assassinated the German Ambassador.
她是我孩子的母亲
She's the mother of my child.
她给我生了孩子 老天呐
She gave birth to my child, for Chrissake.
这里有一份在托布鲁克被抓获的
This is a translated transcript of an interrogation
一个德国军情局军官的审讯笔录译件
of a German Abwehr officer captured in Tobruk.
他招供了很多事 并声称玛丽安·博塞茹尔
Amongst many other things, he claims that Marianne Beauséjour
和她的组员于一九四一年五月
was arrested and executed in May 1941
在巴黎被捕 而她本人被处决了
when the rest of her circuit was captured in Paris.
玛丽安·博塞茹尔这个身份
Marianne Beauséjour's identity
被一个长相相似的德国特工所占用
was then given to a German agent of similar build and coloring.
她被派去了卡萨布兰卡 那里没人认识真正的玛丽安
She was flown to Casablanca, where no one knew the real Marianne.
随后我们调查发现
And it was subsequently discovered
你们俩在卡萨布兰卡
that the German Ambassador
刺杀的那个德国大使是个异见分子
who you assassinated in Casablanca was a dissident.
希特勒原本就想杀了他
Hitler wanted him killed.
这不可能
This is insane.
我们截获的所有通讯情报都要经
All the information in the intercepted communications
你的手发出去
had crossed your desk.
对 都要经我的手发出去
Yes, everything crosses my fucking desk.
马克斯 现在这是个作战任务
Max, this is now an operational mission.
如果玛丽安确实是德国间谍
If Marianne is indeed a German spy...
- 我的妻子不是间谍  - 如果她是
- My wife is not a spy!  - If she is,
我们就必须控制她七十二个小时
we need to keep her in place for 72 hours
用这段时间找出她的联络人
so that we can identify her handler
铲除其他潜伏的间谍
and clean out the rest of her circuit.
不
No.
既然话都讲清楚了
Now we've got that out of the way,
或许我们可以讨论一下
perhaps we could discuss
接下来七十二个小时的行动细节
the operational details of the next 72 hours?
所以我们要启动标准的
So, this is gonna be a standard "blue-dye" procedure,
蓝色染料程序 蓝色染料
blue dye being...
我知道蓝色染料是什么
I know what a "blue-dye" is.
今晚 你会在二十三点零七分接到一个电话
Tonight, you will receive a telephone call at exactly 23:07.
重复一下时间 中校
Repeat the time, Wing Commander.
- 二十三点零七分 长官  - 你接起电话 写下信息 放在
- 23:07, sir.  - You will take the call and you will write down a message
你妻子看得到的地方
somewhere your wife can read it.
情报是假的 只有你会收到
It'll be false information, only you will have it.
但看起来级别很高
But it'll appear to be of a high grade,
所以她要尽快传递出去
so she will have to pass it on quickly.
到下星期一中午时 我们的特工就会破译出敌人周末发出的情报
By midday on Monday, our agents will have decoded enemy traffic from the weekend.
所以如果这条假情报出现在从伦敦发出的情报中
So if the false information is among the batches sent from London,
我们就能确认了
we shall know for sure.
如果你是对的 马克斯 情报译件里就不会有那条情报
If you are right, Max, the information won't appear on the transcripts,
那我们就当没这回事儿
and all this will be forgotten.
但如果证实你的妻子的确是间谍
But if it is proven that your wife is a spy,
我们将立刻启用家属叛国的例行程序
routine procedures in cases of intimate betrayal
例行程序
will apply.
你必须亲手处决她
You will execute her with your own hand,
要是我们发现你有任何共犯行为
and if we discover that you are an accomplice in any way,
你将以叛国罪之名被处决
you will be hanged for high treason.
瓦坦中校 你明白吗
Wing Commander Vatan, do you understand?
我需要他亲口确认他明白
He needs to confirm that he understands
例行程序
routine procedures in...
他明白那个程序 该死
He understands the procedure, damn it.
很好
Good.
马克斯 你一定不能表现出任何反常
Max, it is vital you do nothing differently.
你不要去调查 也不准私自采取行动
You are not to investigate or take matters into your own hands,
明白吗
do you understand?
长官 我…
Sir, I, uh...
我很抱歉 刚刚我表现得太业余了
I apologize for behaving unprofessionally just then.
但是我敢肯定 事实会证明你们搞错了
But I know for a fact you'll be proven wrong.
现在 瓦坦中校 你回家去
Now, Wing Commander, you will go home
装作什么事都没发生
and carry on as if nothing's happened.
你可以走了
You're dismissed.
你去了好久
You were ages.
你也知道
You know how it is.
一旦去了就走不了
Once you get in, you can't get out.
他们要我给一个年轻的飞行员打气
A young pilot needed a pep talk.
还拉我参加了一个作战会议
Then I got dragged into a briefing.
嘿
Hey.
给我的吻哪儿去了
What happened to my kiss?
安娜宝贝儿怎么样了
How's the princess?
睡着呢
Sleeping.
好消息是我周末能休息了
Well, the big news is I definitely have the weekend off.
直到电话响起来
Until the phone rings.
不会
Nope.
整个周末都休息
Definitely free the whole weekend.
那么
So...
可以开宴会了
The party is on.
对 可以开宴会了
Yeah, the party's on.
我们得为明晚的宴会准备些喝的
We'll need to get some drinks for tomorrow night.
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
我明天早上去买
I'll pick some up in the morning.
感觉他们像是在监视着我们
It's like they're watching us.
亲爱的 松下手
Honey... Honey, give me my arm.
亲爱的 让我腾下胳膊
Honey, give me my arm. Give me my arm.
汉普斯特 二三五
Hampstead 235.
我是瓦坦中校
Wing Commander Vatan.
- 亲爱的 你有笔吗  - 没有
- Honey, do you have a pen?  - No.
说吧
Mmm-hmm. Go ahead.
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
好
Yeah.
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
好 我知道了 明早我会发出去
Yeah, I got it. I'll dispatch it in the morning.
别以为我会放你去睡觉 瓦坦先生
Don't think I'm going to let you sleep, Mr. Vatan.
我投入了真感情
I keep the emotions real.
所以才能骗得过
That's why it works.
回床上去
Come back to bed.
不会有事的
It'll be okay.
不会有事的 因为他们搞错了
It'll be okay, because it's not true.
亲爱的
Honey,
你怎么穿军装了
you're in uniform.
对 我要去趟基地 去拿点威士忌
Yeah, I'm gonna pop by the base and pick up some whiskey.
外事机库里藏了五十箱好酒
There's 50 cases of the good stuff stashed in the diplomatic hangar.
拿点没什么的
They won't miss a few.
去商店买不行吗
Why not just go to the shop?
要拿最好的来招待你的知识分子朋友嘛
Nothing but the best for your intellectuals.
我们在酒吧见 买点啤酒
I'll meet you at the pub after and we'll pick up the beer.
好啊
Of course.
- 嗨  - 马克斯
- Hi.  - Max.
你怎么突然来了
What the hell brings you here?
我碰巧路过 请你们参加今晚的宴会
I just dropped by to invite you both to a party tonight.
打个电话不就行了
Why didn't you just phone?
马克斯 你现在这个表情
Max, you look like you did
跟你烧了谷仓那次一模一样
the day that you burned the barn down.
玛丽安在做菜 你们也来参加吧
Marianne's cooking. Why don't you come by?
其实 马克斯 今晚我们可能去不了
Actually, Max, tonight might not be possible.
马克斯
Max!
马克斯 我听说你进V部门了
Max, I heard that you were in V Section.
听着 他们要是让你去做什么自杀任务
If they're offering you some kind of suicide mission,
你可以拒绝的 你知道的
you can say no to them, you know that.
你回去穿衣服吧
You hardly have anything on.
到底怎么了 马克斯
What's happened? Max.
他们要密查玛丽安
They're running a blue-dye on Marianne.
我的天呐
Oh, my God.
但他们搞错了
But it isn't true.
我会证明的
And I will prove it.
今晚我希望你在
I'd like you there tonight.
你好 请问盖伊·桑斯特上校在哪儿
Excuse me. Where can I find Group Captain Guy Sangster?
他在小教堂里 先生
He's in the chapel, sir.
你好 盖伊
Hello, Guy.
马克斯·瓦坦中校
Wing Commander Vatan.
找我有事吗 马克斯
What do you want from me, Max?
我完了 你们把我扔在这里不管了
I'm finished. You people just threw me away.
我有事请你帮忙
I need your help.
- 我想问你个问题  - 是吗
- I have a question.  - Yeah?
没兴趣
Tough.
我相信你不会说出去
I'm trusting you to tell no one about this.
去你的
Fuck you!
我被扔在这儿等死 马克斯
I've been left here to fucking rot, Max!
你说过一九四一年的时候 玛丽安·博塞茹尔
You told me you were smuggled out of France by Marianne Beauséjour.
在法国迪耶普救过你
Dieppe, 1941.
这是她吗
Is this her?
你自个儿老婆的事儿 问我干嘛
Why are you asking me about your wife?
盖伊 拜托 这是她吗
Guy, please, is this her?
他们没告诉你啊
Oh, they didn't tell you.
马克斯
Max.
我的右眼挨了颗子弹
My right eye has been shot out
左眼的视网膜也脱落了
and my left retina is detached.
我现在只能看到
All I can see is
模糊的一片白
a white shape.
该死
Fuck.
你要知道 要不是你派我飞去德国人的
Well, you know, Max, if you hadn't sent me into a strip
高射炮防空区
covered in fucking German AAA!
我自己的亲儿子看到我都吓得尖叫
My own son screamed when he saw me.
对不起 盖伊
I'm sorry, Guy.
马克斯
Max?
德拉马尔
Delamare.
德拉马尔还在迪耶普执行任务
Delamare is still operational in Dieppe.
汉普斯特 二三五
Hampstead 235.
亲爱的 我在机场
Hi, honey, I'm at the strip.
因为之前的空袭 这边需要人献血
They're asking people to give blood after the raid,
我还得一个小时
so I'm gonna be another hour.
我们在酒吧碰头吗
So meet you at the pub after?
好 我请辛克莱尔夫人照顾安娜
Yes, I'll ask Mrs. Sinclair to look after Anna.
好 我爱你 酒吧见
Okay, I love you. I'll see you there.
爱你
Love you.
[问候希特勒]
下士 去搬两箱威士忌放到我车上
Corporal. Put two cases of scotch from the officers' crate in my car.
- 你自己留一瓶  - 是 长官 谢谢
- Keep a bottle for yourself.  - Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
- 今晚谁飞迪耶普  - 亨特 长官
- Who's flying Dieppe tonight?  - Hunter, sir.
- 他在哪里  - 他可能在厕所里 长官
- Where can I find him?  - Try the shithouse, sir.
稍息
At ease.
抱歉 长官
Sorry, sir.
我吃坏肚子了
Something I've eaten.
吃这个药能治好你的肚子
These'll settle your stomach.
我要起飞时再吃安非他命
I'm going to save the amphetamines until takeoff.
返航时吃巴比妥
Then barbiturates when I get back.
如果能返航的话
If I get back.
迪耶普有个我方特务
There's an operative in Dieppe.
叫保罗·德拉马尔 你认识吗？
His name is Paul Delamare. Do you know him?
不认识 这是我的第一次
No. This is my first time.
第一次飞迪耶普
First time to Dieppe?
是第一次深入敌人后方 长官
First time behind enemy lines ever, sir.
德拉马尔负责着陆地点
Paul Delamare runs the landing sites.
你一眼就能认出他 他缺了一只胳膊
You can't miss him, he only has one arm.
他经常喝酒 但不碍事
He's usually had a few, but he's okay.
你要把这个给他 只能给他 只能给缺一只胳膊的人
I want you to give him this. Give it only to him, only to the man with one arm.
[这是玛丽安·博塞茹尔吗？]
让他给你一个答案
Tell him you need an answer.
[这是玛丽安·博塞茹尔吗？]
简单的是 或不是 仅此而已
A simple oui or non. Only that.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
在电报局等我的电话
Wait for my call in the telegraph office.
我午夜时打给你
I'll call you at midnight.
这是机密
This is classified.
绝不能泄露给任何人 明白吗
No one must know, you understand?
是 长官
Yes, sir.
这事非常重要
It's very important.
请相信我 长官
You can count on me, sir.
迪耶普机场那儿到处都是杨树
The fields in Dieppe are lined with poplar trees.
没月光就看不见
They're invisible if there's no moon,
所以你得快点升空
so climb quickly.
我明白 他们跟我说过情况
I know. I've been briefed.
很好
Good.
你在想谁
Who are you thinking about?
我妈妈
My mother.
别
Don't.
想想你爸爸
Think about your father.
他为你自豪
He's proud of you.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
[玫瑰与王冠]
- 噢  - 抱歉 你请
- Oh.  - Sorry. Go ahead.
谢谢
Thank you.
嗨 比利 两杯白兰地
Hi, Billy. Two brandies.
对不起
Sorry.
我订了三箱苦啤酒
I've ordered three crates of bitter.
黑兹尔 把烟斗洗一下
Hazel, filthy pipe smoke.
谢谢
Thank you.
你拿到威士忌了
Did you get the whiskey?
拿到了 是丘吉尔喝的上等货
I did. Churchill's own.
丈夫会在自己抽烟前
A husband would offer his wife a cigarette...
先给妻子一根烟
before lighting his own.
你确实献了血
You did give blood!
很好
Good.
我以为你跟情妇幽会去了
I thought perhaps you were out with your mistress.
那就能解释你昨晚对我的不同了
It would explain why you were different with me last night.
不同
Different?
在床上
In bed.
感觉不一样
It felt different.
很好
Good.
不好意思
Excuse me!
我们几位特别想看
Me and my mates would really love to see
你们两位女士接吻
you two ladies kiss each other.
真亲了
I don't believe it!
她真够疯的
That was crazy!
马克斯 宴会太棒了
Max, this is splendid.
玛丽安
Marianne!
宴会特别棒 超级棒
Wonderful party! Brilliant!
喝够了吗
Getting enough to drink?
真会说笑 老家伙
Very funny, old man.
不好意思 我家有花园
Hey, excuse me. We have a garden for that.
出去亲热
Take it outside, please.
好了 你们两个 出去亲热
Okay. You two, outside. Outside.
来这儿
Come here.
我的客人表现得太差了
My people are behaving so badly.
我以为他们会吃点东西
I thought they would eat something,
而不是忙着喝酒亲热
not just drink and have sex.
一半的人我都不认识
Half of them I don't even know.
看来汉普斯特这儿的消息传的很快
I think word spread around Hampstead.
这是伦敦 还是战争时期
C'est Londres. C'est la guerre.
你去确认下没人在安娜的房间里乱搞好吗
Would you go check no one is actually fucking in Anna's room?
好
Sure.
马克斯 马克斯 马克斯
Max! Max, Max.
噢 噢
Ooh. Ooh.
对不起
Sorry.
好了
Listen.
听着 他们说你要执行任务
I've been briefed that you're operational,
但是 他们没告诉我是什么任务
but I haven't been told why you're operational.
听着 我觉得作为朋友
Now, look, I thought as a friend
我应该稍微提醒你一下
I ought to just give you a word of warning.
要是V部门给你的任务
If the job V Section are offering you is
就是大家现在说的那个
the one everyone's talking about...
马克斯 如果他们要你在诺曼底登陆日
Max, if they want you to run the resistance...
领导法国抵抗运动
in France on D-Day,
他们不会叫你过去
you should know they wouldn't just call you
搞个面试
in for a job interview.
而是瞒着你考验你
They would test you somehow.
考验
Test?
- 怎么考验  - 这可就大大超出我的安全级别了
- How?  - Way, way above my security clearance, old man.
但是 我要是你 我会坚决拒绝的
But if I were you, I'd tell them to stick their job.
小心 玛格丽特
Careful, Margaret.
马克斯
Max.
我最后还是来了
I was able to make it after all.
弗兰克 没想到你会来
Frank! I didn't expect you.
麻烦你帮忙让这群人冷静点儿吧
Please introduce a little sobriety to the affair.
我可没打算做这种事儿
I wasn't planning on doing anything of the sort.
给我一大杯威士忌和苏打水好吗
A large whiskey and soda, if you please.
去拿酒好吗 亲爱的
Would you get it, honey?
他一脸有事的样子
Frank still has his work face on.
你养鸡 对不对
You keep chickens, don't you?
弗兰克 你知道得太多了
Frank, you know too much.
带我去看你的鸡 马克斯
Show me your chickens, Max.
你故意而且明目张胆地违抗了命令
You willfully and blatantly disobeyed orders.
先是去找了盖伊·桑斯特
First you visit Guy Sangster
把他气的七窍生烟
and burst half his bloody stitches, then...
弗兰克 要是你的妻子 你能相信V部门吗
Frank, if it was your wife, would you trust V Section?
亚当·亨特的飞机三个小时前被击毁了
Adam Hunter's Lysander was shot to pieces three hours ago.
在着陆点那儿 他在飞机上
On the ground. With him in it!
他死了
He's dead!
就因为他在那儿待得太久了 要从一个醉鬼的
Because he stayed too long waiting for an answer
嘴巴里等到一个答案
to a question from a drunk.
弗兰克 告诉我
Frank, tell me.
- 这是个游戏吗  - 游戏
- Is this a game?  - A game?
游戏
A game.
考验
A test.
我刚刚在跟马克斯说
I was just saying to Max
他在办公室里干得如鱼得水
that he's taken to office life like a duck to water.
我不知道
I wouldn't know.
我很少见到他
I hardly see him.
好了 亲爱的 我们跳舞吧
Come on, honey, let's dance.
弗兰克带了坏消息来？
Frank brought you bad news?
又死了一个飞行员
Another boy dead.
我感觉应该比死人更严重吧
Something more than that, I think.
我问布里奇特你是不是不对劲
I asked Bridget if there was something wrong with you,
她说你没事
and she said you were fine.
她可不像我们这样专门学过骗人
But she's not trained to lie like you and me.
我们有个任务失败了 我不能多说
We've had a setback. I can't talk about it.
烤箱里有东西糊了
I think something's burning in the oven!
好像是俄式炖肉的味道
It could be the stroganoff.
你先退下 上尉
Stand down, Flight Lieutenant.
- 玛格丽特  - 长官
- Margaret?  - Sir.
明天还往迪耶普空投吗
Is the Dieppe drop still on tomorrow?
我想应该会的 长官
I believe it is, sir.
- 天气情况怎么样  - 晴天 长官
- Forecast?  - Clear skies, sir.
嘿
Hey.
那个抽烟斗的 他是谁
The man with the pipe. Who is he?
他叫隆巴德
His name is Lombard.
在商业街上开了家珠宝店
He has a jewelry shop on the high street.
他向我推销一个钻石胸针
He was trying to sell me a diamond broach.
不过我说我们破产了
But I told him we're broke.
你要去哪儿
Hey, where are you going?
- 马克斯  - 玛丽安
- Max!  - Marianne.
我想跟你说点事
I really need to speak to you.
杰弗里 你喝醉了
Oh. Jeffrey, you're too drunk.
嘿
Hey.
你的妻子改主意了
Your wife changed her mind.
你说的是耳环吗
You mean about the earrings.
不不不 我想卖给她的是胸针
No, no, no, I was trying to sell her a broach.
不过我确实有些漂亮的耳环
I do have some beautiful earrings.
而且可以给你个优惠价
I can offer you a very good price.
马克斯
Max.
不用了 隆巴德先生 我们真的破产了
It's okay, Mr. Lombard. We really are broke.
晚安
Good night.
我去看看安娜
I'll have to get Anna.
- 我没听到警报  - 警报怎么没响
- I didn't hear a siren.  - Where were the sirens?
总算响了
Now they sound the alarm.
这什么警报啊 总是慢两拍
Bloody ARP, always two steps behind.
赶快把灯给关掉
Get these bloody lights off!
他们又轰炸东区了
They're targeting the East End again.
这一片应该没事
We should be all right here.
马克斯 别再搞事了
Max, no more.
拜托
Please?
到星期一上午
By Monday morning, we'll...
我们就知道结果了
We'll know for sure.
去休息一下吧
Try and get some rest.
- 弗兰克  - 这不是游戏
- Frank?  - It's not a game.
就算它是
Even if it is,
V部门也不会告诉你的
V Section wouldn't tell you.
对不对
Would they?
他们不会告诉你的 弗兰克
They wouldn't tell you, Frank.
看
Look!
击落一架 好耶
We got one! Yes!
飞机朝我们这边来了
It's heading right towards us!
大家快找掩护
Everyone take cover!
蹲下
Get down!
马克斯
Max!
你去让大家散了好吗
Will you get rid of everyone?
好
Yeah.
马克斯
Max.
明天我们能陪安娜一整天
Tomorrow we have a whole day with Anna.
我们忘记战争
Let's forget the war.
好好地度过这一天吧
Let's make the best day ever.
好
Yeah.
我很愿意
I'd like that.
谁要先跳呀
Who's gonna jump first?
我生火了 过来跟我们一起坐吧
I've lit a fire. Come sit with us.
这个吗
This one?
空军上尉
Flight Lieutenant!
我有个好消息 今晚可以休息了
I have good news. You have the night off.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
你在干什么 为什么把引擎关了
What the hell are you doing? Why have you switched off the engine?
保罗·德拉马尔在哪儿
Where is Paul Delamare?
保罗·德拉马尔
Paul Delamare ??
- 他进监狱了  - 什么
- He's in jail.  - What?
德拉马尔 他进监狱了
Delamare is in jail.
什么 是盖世太保抓的
What? Gestapo?
不 警察抓的
No, local police.
他又喝醉了
Drunk as usual.
带我去监狱
Take me to the jail.
我们走
Let’s go
里面有多少警察
How many inside?
今晚只有一个
This time of night, only one.
求求你别杀我
I don't want any trouble!
保罗·德拉马尔在哪儿
Where is Paul Delamare?
三号牢房
Cell number three.
- 你在这儿看着他  - 没问题
- You're here to see him.  - no problem
求求你别杀我
I don't want any trouble.
去后面守着
Go back and watch
打开
Open it.
该死 该死的 怎么回事
Damn it, damn it. What's going on?
不好意思 德拉马尔先生 我在赶时间
I'm sorry, Mr. Delamare. I'm in a hurry.
接下来我要说的是最高机密 最高机密
What I'm going to say is top secret.
- 你懂英语吗  - 不懂 怎么了
- Do you speak English?   - No. Why?
这到底怎么回事
What the hell is going on here?
看 你看 仔细看
Look. Look closely.
照片上的这个女人是玛丽安·博塞茹尔吗
Is the woman in this photograph Marianne Beauséjour?
谁
Who?
玛丽安·博塞茹尔
Marianne Beauséjour!
看着 是她吗
Look! Is it her?
酒 把酒瓶给我
Give me the bottle!
回答我 我就给你酒瓶
Yes or no, and then you get a drink.
玛丽安·博塞茹尔
Marianne Beauséjour?
Marianne Beauséjour.
玛丽安·博塞茹尔
Marianne Beauséjour...
看着
Look!
是 是她
Yes. It's her.
- 是吗  - 把酒瓶给我
- Yes?  - Now let me have a drink.
再看看 你确定
Look again. Are you sure?
去你的
Fuck you!
看着 看着
Look. Look!
- 这个女人就是她  - 是吗
- She look the same. Yeah.  - Yes?
她喜欢笑 棕色头发
She laughs a lot. Brown hair.
- 棕色眼睛 对吗  - 对 棕色眼睛
- And she has brown eyes, yes?  - Right. Brown eyes.
她是蓝眼睛 混蛋 是蓝眼睛
She's got blue eyes! God damn it, blue eyes!
对 对 我就是说蓝眼睛
Right! I mean blue.
别耍我 德拉马尔
Don't you fuck with me, Delamare.
我之前说错了
I made a mistake.
- 看着  - 她的眼睛是蓝的
- Look!  - She has blue eyes.
我认识她 真的
I know her. Sure.
她是聚会上的焦点
She is the life of the party.
继续
Go on.
她会画画
And she paints.
画画 对 她画什么
Paints, yes. She paints what?
她画的水彩画 非常美
Wonderful watercolors.
没错
That's right.
- 把酒给我  - 没问题
- Give me the bottle.  - That's right.
德国佬
The Krauts!
她弹钢琴的样子宛如女神
And she plays the piano like a goddess.
钢琴
Piano?
别动
Don't move.
朋友们 谁想抽点美国香烟
Who wants some American cigarettes?
嘿
Hey!
什么
Quoi?
德国佬有时候会过来
Sometimes the Krauts...
找我们要美国香烟
...they come to get American cigarettes.
什么美国香烟
American cigarettes?
我们从反抗军那没收的
We confiscate them from the Resistance.
我记得玛丽安
I remember Marianne.
我第一次遇见她
I remember when I met her.
是在多尔多涅的一个咖啡馆
It was in a café. In Dordogne.
咖啡馆里有一群德国士兵
The place was full of German soldiers.
- 我们得走了  - 等等 等等
- We gotta go!  - Wait!
里面有一架钢琴
There was a piano.
她走了过去
She went to it
弹奏了《马赛曲》
and played La Marseillaise
就在那些德国佬的面前
in front of all those Germans!
出发吧 祖国的孩子们
Set out, the children of the motherland
闭嘴 闭嘴
Shut up, shut up
皮埃尔
Hey, Pierre!
好彩香烟
Lucky Strike?
快点开门
Open the door
你有那烟吗
Do you have the cigarettes?
把烟给他
Give them to him.
喂 皮埃尔
Allo, Pierre?
皮埃尔 是我
Pierre, c'est moi!
开门 开门
Open the door
游击队
Guerrilla detachment
监狱后面
Behind the jail!
是游击队的人 他们往后面跑了
The Resistance are running behind the jail!
德国佬在广场上
The Krauts are in the square!
给我个手榴弹
A grenade.
这里 从这个门走
Here, walk through the door
玛丽安
Marianne,
你跟我出去一趟
I need you to come with me.
把安娜交给保姆 你现在跟我出去
Drop off Anna and come with me now, please.
你到底在做什么
What the hell are you doing?
玛丽安
Marianne...
我想听你给我弹钢琴
I want you to play the piano for me.
你想什么
You want what?
你为什么突然要我弹钢琴
Why on earth would you want me to play the piano?
我想让你弹钢琴 因为我爱你
I want you to play the piano because I love you.
你到底在说什么
What are you talking about?
你熬了一夜 我们回家吧
You haven't slept. Let's go home.
我想听你弹《马赛曲》
I want you to play La Marseillaise.
虽然你以前也让我做过奇奇怪怪的事
Now, you have asked me some strange things...
弹
Play.
玛丽安·博塞茹尔一九四一年在一家咖啡馆里
Marianne Beauséjour played La Marseillaise
当着德国人的面弹了《马赛曲》
in a café full of Germans in '41.
我想听你给我弹
I want you to play it for me.
我知道这件事
I know the story.
她是一个非常勇敢的女人
She was a very brave woman.
我以为他们找不到我了
I thought they wouldn't find me here.
可他们找到了
But they did.
他们拿安娜威胁我
And they threatened Anna.
我 我真的很抱歉
And I'm... And I'm so sorry.
我真的很抱歉
I am so sorry.
你发了吗
Did you send it?
那条情报你发了吗
The message! Did you send it?
发了
Yes.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你告诉我
I need to know,
这是真的吗
is this real?
你爱我吗
Do you love me?
我爱你 我爱你
I love you. I love you.
我在卡萨布兰卡就爱上了你
I've loved you since Casablanca.
好了 听我说 我们接下来这样做
Okay, listen to me. This is how it will be.
我们一起去梅迪辛哈特
There is a Medicine Hat
它就在瑞士 或者秘鲁 或者管它在什么鬼地方
in Switzerland or Peru or wherever the hell.
我们去不了的
We won't make it.
再过一个小时 V部门就会让我杀了你
If we stay one more hour, V Section's gonna order me to kill you.
如果我不答应 我们俩都会死
And when I refuse, they're gonna shoot us both.
明白吗
You understand?
我们现在就走
We go now.
我们得去接安娜
We have to get Anna.
玛丽安呢
Where is Marianne?
你拿我的孩子当人质
You used my child as collateral.
你也毫不逊色 瓦坦中校
You've done far worse, Wing Commander Vatan.
还有谁在监视我们
Who else is watching us?
我是第三帝国的特工
Ich bin einen agent des Reiches.
我只能告诉你我的…
I will only give you my...
过来 别怕 宝贝儿
Come here, sweetheart.
别怕 宝贝儿 别怕 没事了
It's okay, honey. It's okay. It's okay.
[隆巴德珠宝]
好 长官 您可以过去了
Very good, sir. You're free to pass.
在这儿等着
Wait here.
结束了 马克斯！
It's over, Max!
蓝色染料程序证明她是间谍
The blue-dye came back positive.
你已经知道了 是不是
But you already know that, don't you?
弗兰克 等等
Frank, wait!
等等 你听我解释
Wait! Let me explain.
- 我已经清除了其他潜伏间谍  - 马克斯·瓦坦
- The circuit's been cleaned.  - Max Vatan,
以国王陛下乔治六世之名
in the name of His Majesty King George VI...
是他们逼她的 弗兰克
They had her boxed in, Frank!
我宣判你犯了叛国罪
I charge you with high treason...
不 求你了
No! Please!
协助并教唆德国间谍
...for aiding and abetting the German spy
玛丽安·博塞茹尔
known as Marianne Beauséjour.
弗兰克 她是被逼的 他们拿安娜 拿我们全家威胁她
Frank, she had no choice. They threatened Anna. They would have killed us all!
马克斯 你已经疯了吗
Max, have you lost your mind?
她是德国间谍
She's a German spy!
我不会让你动她的 弗兰克
I won't let you do this, Frank.
我的任务完成了 我杀了潜伏间谍
I've done my duty. We've cleaned up the circuit.
该死 他们掌握了重要情报
They had valuable information, damn you!
她是被逼的 他们要杀安娜
She had no choice! They threatened Anna!
如果你不想被处决
If you want to walk away from this,
你知道应该怎么做
then do what needs to be done.
她是被逼的 德国人威胁她
She had no choice. They had her boxed in.
拿我们全家人的性命威胁她
They would've killed us all.
V部门才不管这个
The Section won't care.
他们要杀安娜
They threatened Anna!
为了你的孩子 不要自己找死
For your child's sake, don't throw your life away!
我完成任务了 你让开
We did our duty. Just walk away.
让开 弗兰克
Walk away, Frank.
马克斯
Max.
我爱你 我的魁北瓜
Je t'aime, mon Québécois.
我爱你
I love you.
好好照顾她
Take good care of her.
解除戒备
Stand down.
空军中校马克斯·瓦坦亲手处决了敌方间谍
Wing Commander Vatan executed the enemy agent with his own hand.
你们就这么报告
That is how you will report it.
这是命令
That is an order.
我亲爱的安娜宝贝儿
My dearest, darling Anna.
我在一个星期日的晚上 在伦敦写下了这封信
I'm writing this on a Sunday night in London.
当你读到这封信时
If you're reading this,
也许你会对我感到陌生
then you barely knew me
也许根本想不起来我是谁
and may have no memory of who I am.
我是你的妈妈
I am your mother.
你出生在战争时期的一次空袭中
You were born in an air raid in the middle of a war
是爸爸妈妈的爱情结晶
to two people who loved each other.
我们在汉普斯特的这栋房子里
Our year together in the house in Hampstead
度过的一年是我一生中最幸福的时光
has been the happiest time of my life.
今天 你学会了走路
Today you took your first steps.
我很感激有你爸爸陪在我身边
I am so grateful that I saw you walk for the first time
看到你第一次走路
with your father by my side.
马克斯 我的爱人
Max, my love,
你就是我的世界
you are my world.
我希望你能够原谅我
I hope you will be able to forgive me.
我希望你能去梅迪辛哈特
And I hope you make it to Medicine Hat.
我在脑海里想象过它的样子
I have a picture of it in my mind,
我希望安娜能亲眼看到它
and I pray Anna's eyes will see it.
我可爱的女儿
My beautiful daughter,
我全心全意地爱着你
I love you with all my heart.
我希望你这一生能平平安安的
I hope you will live your life in peace.
我知道你爸爸会好好照顾你的 这样我就能安息了
I rest knowing your father will take good care of you.
永远爱你的妈妈
I remain your loving mother,
玛丽安·瓦坦
Marianne Vatan.